Preliminary Inventory to the Russia. Legatsiia (Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, Germany) Records, 1902-1908
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Legatsiia (Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, Germany) Records,
1902-1908
34003
Russia. Legatsiia (Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, Germany)
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, orders, reports, and printed matter, relating to Russian-German relations
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1934.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Germany; Germany--Foreign relations--Russia; Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach (Germany); Russia; Russia--Foreign relations--Germany
Container List
- Foreign Office political reports sent out to Russian Representatives abroad (Box 1)
  - 1902
  - 1903
  - 1904
- Foreign Office orders of the day
  - 1902-03
  - 1904
  - 1905
  - 1906-08
- Foreign Office correspondence, instructions and dispositions to the Weimar Legation
- St. Petersburg Police Department circular letters, 1903-06
- Recall of Chamberlain Baron Budberg from Weimar, 1903
- Nomination of Mr. Prosor as Minister Resident in Weimar and Altenburg and his recall from, 1903-04
- Correspondence between Mr. Prosor and other Russian diplomatic representatives on the subject of his nomination, 1903-04 (Box 2)
- Nomination of Baron Grewenitz as Minister Resident of Weimar, 1904-05
- Correspondence regarding the remittance of credential letters to diplomatic representatives, 1903-04
- Mr. Prosor's political reports, 1903-04
- Baron Grewenitz's political reports, 1904-07
- Corresondence regarding secret codes, 1903-06
- Negotiations with the Court of the Grand Duke of Saxe-Weimar
  - 1903-07
  - 1905-07
- Negotiations with the Court of the Grand Duke of Saxe-Altenburg, 1904-06
- Foreign Office, St. Petersburg, political reports, 1903
- Russian workmen, 1905-06
- Russian students in various schools and universities, 1905
- Decorations, reports pertaining to the granting of
- Correspondence, general, 1903-07